hey everybody welcome to this a2 english
listening practice video you can use
this video to practice your listening
and comprehension as i speak before we
start remember to download the listening
time podcast and if you want my
specialized training to help you improve
your listening then become a member at
patreon.com
listeningtime if you become a member
you'll get my seminars where i train you
to listen more effectively and
understand native speakers and if you
become a listening time family member
you'll get my advanced podcast episodes
so you can train to become an advanced
listener ok today we're going to talk
about emotions we all feel a wide range
of emotions
and it's important to understand our
emotions so let's start off with
positive emotions let's talk about the
most famous emotion happiness this is
the emotion that all of us like when
we're happy this means that we're
satisfied we feel good and we're able to
smile so what makes people happy well
there could be tons of things
some of the most common might include
having good relationships enjoying your
job and doing fun things but honestly i
think the most important factor is
feeling like you have a purpose in life
if you feel like you have a reason to
wake up in the morning then you probably
experience happiness quite often
okay next let's talk about excitement
this is one of my favorite emotions when
you're excited you can't wait for the
future you feel happy and optimistic
about something you're gonna do or about
something that's gonna happen
so what makes people excited again there
could be tons of things
for example i know that i get excited
when i think about my goals for the
future it's fun and exciting to think
about what i can accomplish
i also feel excited when i'm gonna
travel
i really love planning trips and it
makes me excited to research the places
where i'm gonna go
alright let's talk about one other
positive emotion
relief
relief is the emotion you feel when some
uncertain situation ends in a positive
way for example imagine that you're
worried that you have some serious
health problem but then the doctor tells
you that you're okay and there's nothing
to worry about
you feel a sense of relief when you hear
that this can be a really strong emotion
because you release all the worry that
you were feeling i love this feeling
okay now let's talk about a few negative
emotions
first anger this is the emotion that
none of us like feeling it's normal to
feel angry at times especially when
someone does something really bad
however it's not good to feel angry all
the time this shouldn't be an emotion
that stays with us when we get mad it
should only be for a limited time we
should be able to get over this anger
when the bad situation passes here's one
tip i can give don't go to bed angry try
to resolve this problem before the end
of the day
this will make your life a lot better
another negative emotion is sadness no
one likes feeling sad but unfortunately
this is another normal emotion
we need to feel sad about certain things
but i think that if you talk about this
with someone that you love it really
helps you deal with your sadness we need
to be able to express this feeling and
then we can move on
one more negative emotion is fear this
is one of my least favorite emotions
there are some things in life that scare
us when you were a kid you were probably
afraid of the dark or maybe you're still
afraid of spiders but there are many
other worse fears that affect our lives
they can make us scared to do things and
they can make us feel really stressed so
of course it's good to try to overcome
our fears
okay that's all for today remember to
download my free listening time podcast
and become a member at patreon.com
listeningtime to receive my specialized
training which will help you understand
native speakers and if you want to reach
an advanced level of listening then
become a listening time family member so
you can train your listening with my
advanced podcast episodes also subscribe
to the channel click on the bell and
follow us on instagram i'll see you next
time
you